EUGENE KIM

Johns Creek, GA 30097 • Phone: 410-409-0516 • <u>ekim1707@gmail.com</u> www.eugenekimportfolio.com/ • <u>github.com/ekim1707</u> • <u>linkedin.com/in/eugene-kim-1707</u>

JAVASCRIPT SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Expert, disciplined learner of new technologies and languages as pertaining to software development project goals; passionately curious of all disciplines relating to progress and general welfare of the community. Strong grasp of agile work environments and flexibility to adapt in order to optimize overall success. Strong understanding of position of physicians/medical providers in respect to clients; life-long student of the health sciences and medicine. Proven track record of stellar work ethic and devotion to team success at every step along the journey.

Expertise

- Full-Stack Web Development
- SQL Queries & Data Modeling
- Strong Analytical/Critical Thinking Skills
- Ability to Learn New Technologies Quickly
- Application Development & Collaboration
- Debugging/Troubleshooting
- Understanding of Healthcare Industry
- Fluency in Medical Terminology

Professional Experience

React Intern, HEARBK, Atlanta, GA

Dec 2019 to Present

Collaborating remotely with lead developer on two-person development team to build React.js mobile application to pair with existing website for Atlanta-based startup intending to provide a platform for aspiring artists to be heard by uploading their music and gaining recognition from top music influencers and fans.

Project Highlights:

- Provided bulk of front-end written to be compatible with back-end of lead developer.
- Communicated with lead developer and company owner to make all necessary changes for final product design.
- Following official release of mobile application to public, continuing to work in role geared toward maintaining the product, as well as assisting in any future innovation efforts.

Freelance Web Developer, SELF-EMPLOYED, Johns Creek, GA

Sept 2019 to Present

Independently-run freelance full-stack web development services (remote/in-person).

Project Highlights:

- In process of remotely building full-stack website, including physician's portal and SQL database, for medical office where previously employed as medical assistant.
- In planning stages of developing a handful of smaller-scale websites for other clients.

EUGENE KIM
Page 2

Professional Experience (continued):

Assistant Manager, THE TUTORING CENTER, Johns Creek, GA

Nov 2018 to May 2019

Served as second-in-command for owner of local tutoring center franchise specializing in instruction of K-12/SAT/ACT students. Self-sufficiently managed front desk, open/closed facility on daily basis, and ran center independently when necessary.

Project Highlights:

- Coordinated all tutors; managed all classroom procedures.
- Taught whenever necessary; served as PRN tutor for higher-level SAT/ACT students.
- Implemented use of Google/Amazon learning apps during all primary education classes.

Senior Analyst Advisor, IFPA INC., Teaneck, NJ

Sept 2016 to Nov 2017

Served as expert manager of company's master database and led all inventory management efforts. IFPA is a large-scale, worldwide parts-manufacturer and distributer, most renown for being the main supplier for Herman Miller.

Project Highlights:

- Changed organizational scheme for storing inventory data; re-wrote master database.
- Aided in research efforts regarding product development and cost allocation.
- Attended executive meetings and gave presentations regarding ideas and research findings.

Healthcare Experience

PRN/Tech, CCDDC, Westminster, MD

Aug 2015 to Oct 2016

Spent start of second semester of RN program working with a 10+ member patient-care unit of Carroll County Digestive Disease Center to provide optimal care to all admitted endoscopy patients.

Project Highlights:

- Successfully prioritized and balanced all required duties throughout each shift.
- Received further training of and eventually mastered proper patient-care techniques.

RN Program Student, HCC, Columbia, MD

Jan 2015 to May 2016

Attended three semesters of the RN program at Howard Community College.

Project Highlights:

- Coordinated with nurses to provide full patient care throughout acute/long-term care facilities.
- Practiced proper documentation methods and adhering to specific healthcare provider protocol.

PT Shadow, CENTRAL MARYLAND REHABILITATION, Westminster, MD May 2011 to June 2013 Shadowed several physical therapists and physical therapist assistants and assisted when needed.

Phone: 410-409-0516 • ekim1707@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/eugene-kim-1707

EUGENE KIM
Page 3

Education

DigitalCrafts, Atlanta, GA

Certificate in Software Engineering, Sept 2019

Howard Community College, Columbia, MD

UMBC, Baltimore, MD

Bachelor of Arts in Biology, GPA: 3.296, Aug 2012

Boston College, Chestnut Hill, MA

Software Development Portfolio

PeachtreeData.com, demo, website, github

Sept 2019

Wrote social-media/life-database site with connections, newsfeed, media-page, notepad, more.

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, Express, PostgreSQL, React, and Redux.

Widowmaker Site, demo, website, github

Sept 2019

Wrote site for the video game Overwatch featuring hero overviews, video gallery, and forum.

• HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, and React.

Insta.id, demo, website, github

Aug 2019

Led 3-person development team in building an app to serve as an everyday ID-verification tool.

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, Express, and PostgreSQL.

OWRPG, demo, github

July 2019

Wrote large-scale, multi-layered RPG game incorporating the video game Overwatch.

Python.

Technology Summary

Applications: Adobe XD, Microsoft Office, Trello, Medical Mastermind, gGastro

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Sass, SQL, Python, C#

Frameworks: Node.js, Express.js, React.js, Redux.js, Bootstrap

Other: jQuery, RESTful API, AWS, Heroku, Netlify

Leadership and Awards

Phi Theta Kappa Honors Society, Howard Community College, March 2015 Secretary of Student Government, Howard Community College, Aug 2013 to Dec 2013 Co-chair of Student Senate, Howard Community College, Aug 2013 to Dec 2013 Sigma Alpha Lambda National Leadership and Honors Organization, UMBC, Aug 2009 Golden Key International Honors Society, UMBC, Sept 2008

Phone: 410-409-0516 • ekim1707@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/eugene-kim-1707